David Wagenhurst

(972) 415-8763 wagenhurstd@gmail.com GitHub Profile Linkedin Profile Personal Portfolio Dallas, TX

I am a data scientist with nearly 5 years of experience as a Commercial Financial Services professional. I understand the importance of finance to both businesses and individuals and want to utilize my skill set for the betterment of others. Skilled in large data analysis and configuration, machine learning, corporate trust transactions, and property accounting

SKILLS

Technical Skills:

- Python: pandas, sklearn, seaborn, selenium
- PostgreSQL querying
- Streamlit
- Microsoft Excel functions: Macros, VLOOKUPs, developing conditional formulas, and pivot tables

EXPERIENCE

General Assembly

Data Science Fellow

March 2022 – June 2022

- 500+ hour Data Science Immersive with a focus on true-to-life applications of data science and its principles.
- Experience includes data acquisition, cleaning, preprocessing, predictive modeling, constructing visualizations, and project presentation.
- Individual and group projects covering a variety of topics and techniques including; nlp, linear regression, scraping, sql databases and classification.

Greystar

Property Accountant

March 2021 – March 2022

- Managed full-cycle G/L accounting and reporting for seven large multi-family portfolios
- Compiled and analyzed financial information in preparation for entry into various financial statements and accounting reports for presentation to client and audit review
- Analyzed and reviewed accounting and financial resources for property acquisitions, dispositions, and closings and budgets and expenditures for local, state, federal, private funding, contracts, grants, and other corporate financial and accounting transactions

Bank of America

Sr. Operations Analysis

October 2017 - March 2021

- Executed Private Bank custody services for over 30,200 individual securities within the Corporate Actions and Class Actions unit for over 100k monthly transactions
- Processed and reconciled corporate actions including cash & stock mergers, spin-offs, rights distributions, liquidations, stock dividends, partial defeasances, reverse splits, and stock exchanges valued at over \$10 million
- Configured data for analysis of account tax lot structure and cost basis transactions.

EDUCATION

The University of Texas at Austin

August 2013 - May 2017

- Bachelor of Science in Mathematics
 - Mathematical Sciences, Specialization in Statistics, Probability & Data Analysis
- Business Certificate

General Assembly

March 2022 – June 2022

• Data Science Immersive